TEACHER, 5TH AND 6TH GRADE SCIENCE/LITERATURE/S.S./HR Professional Summary

My ecologically minded worldview and my strongly developed science teaching skills will not only complement any curriculum but instill in my students respect for life in all its mysterious ways and a desire of conservation through advocacy and communication. I have been told to have a way to empower my pupils and surge their motivation. My personal experiences and background have helped me develop a multicultural attitude and understanding of diversity. Teaching fills me up, is immensely satisfying and it's when I'm at my best. In order to have more time to focus on my Ph.D. studies I decided to leave my teaching position last year, take on a Graduate Assistant position at Barry University, and dedicate myself to the doctoral process. After the summer semester, I will have completed all my course work and in August I will take my Comp. exam. It is my goal to complete my Ph.D. in Curriculum and Instruction by 2019. Strict, but fair Strong classroom management strategies Experiments and handson activities' connoisseur Technology savvy Lifelong love for learning Diploma in Business Administration from renowned institute in The Netherlands I was born in Germany, raised in The Netherlands and hold the equivalent of an AA in Business Administration in three languages from The Schoevers Institute in The Netherlands, as well as certificates in restaurant and hospitality management, personal training, aerobics instruction, and commercial journalism. During my younger years I traveled extensively, lived and worked in several countries, worked in businesses and the hospitality industry and acquired excellent people skills. In 1987 I moved to the U.S.A., married in 1988, and hold a Permanent Alien Resident Card. I am a breastfeeding peer counselor trained by WIC and hold a CPR certificate. In addition, I actively update my teaching skills through professional development and hold a valid Professional Teaching Certificate as well as a Clinical Educator Certificate. I raised three children; girls (26 and 22), boy (24.) and have been married to my husband Joe for 30 years. In addition, after I had my children, I returned to school for a career change, earning a BS and then a MS. My next goals are, completing my Ph.D. in C&I, participate in research projects, publish articles, and write a book.

Skills

Work History

Broward County Public Schools Teacher, 5th and 6th grade Science/Literature/S.S./HR

- 2006 till 2017 5th literature, 5th and 6th science, 5th and 6th Science Lab, and 5th Social Studies.
- W.J.
- Brian Elementary 2004-2006 4th grade AE/Gifted All Subjects.

Broward Estates Elementary teacher for 4th grade AE // January 2003 to January 2004

- 4th, and 5th Gifted/Highly G.
- All Subjects.

Miami Shores Elementary School Pool Substitute // January 2000 to January 2001

- CLP Conference Leading a Meaning Full Life: Teaching Happiness and Well-Being in the K-12 Classroom Relationships Presentation 2016 Lego WeDo How to integrate simple robotics in the elementary classroom peer presentation 2015 SERVICE CLP Elementary Division, taking part in community activities with elementary CLP ambassadors (Arbor Day, Unity Day).
- LEADERSHIP AND COMPETENCIES Science Chair Develop and modify Science curriculum, deciding on the use of a multitude of materials, including text books, assisting the Tech Department in choice of software and digital media and teaching aids.
- Holding monthly meetings with science colleagues to discuss relevant science matters and stay alert to current science happenings, professional development opportunities and funding.
- Science teacher Teach General Science to 5th and Earth and Space Science to 6th.
- Plan and prepare for experiments, activities, and real life trials.
- Co-teach with the Science Lab teacher to align Science Lab curriculum with classroom Science curriculum.
- STEAM Participate as an active member of the Cushman STEAM Team (Science, Technology, Engineering, Art, and Math) by assisting in
 the design of the brand new STEAM Lab facility, being a part of the effort to integrate STEAM lessons throughout all grades, attending
 workshops and conferences preparing for "The STEAM-age," and educate and motivate faculty to become more STEAM oriented.
- Technology Skilled in innovative forms of technology and the application of such in the classroom on a daily basis including the creation of Digital Portfolios Robotics Robotic Club Instructor/Coordinator.
- Completed a week-long robotics workshop at the Carnegie Melon Robotics Academy in Pittsburgh (2013) Classroom Skilled in classroom
 management, through setting high Management expectations and implementing student accountability as well as incorporating the suggestions
 of the authors of "Love and Logic", "The Habits of Mind", and "Discipline without Stress." In addition, I am a fan of The Cushman
 philosophy of instilling "industry, courtesy, responsibility, and scholarship" in students.
- I have raised three children of my own, which taught me more about classroom management than any lectures I ever attended.
- Prof.
- Dev.
- Differentiated Instruction Institute conference, Habits of Mind, Love and Logic, 21st Century Curriculum, yearly NSTA Conferences, To Push or Not to Push, CLP Conferences, FCIS and FETC conferences, Education Expo Conferences, Carnegie Mellon Robotics Academy, Clinical Education, Mandarin Chinese for beginners Social Studies For many years, I also taught 5th grade social studies starting with the history of native Americans, the first explorers and ending just before the American Revolution; including monitoring the completion of a year-long and multifaceted project called "Heritage Day." This is a cross curricular Project/Event that ends in a whole day bazar with heritage costumes and foods, including a three-minute speech delivered by each student introducing their family's heritage country.
- Lead education interns in their final preparation of becoming full time teachers by introducing them to engaging lessons, a variety of classroom management strategies, and how to organize the daily task of a home room teacher.

- Modify lessons according to the needs of all students and co-teach Social Studies with the 5th grade Laura Cushman Academy teacher.
- Guide students in using the latest technology; my 5th and 6th grade students all had a laptop they used daily for projects, homework, research, presentations, and other forms of educational communication.
- Robotics ClubInstruct students in building and programming Lego Mindstorm NXT and Lego V3 robots.
- Confident Young Ladies Club founder and instructor; creating an environment where girls can be girls and learn old-fashion craft skills, learn
 about fashion and elegance, and simultaneously create opportunities to empower young women, discuss daily social issues, and prepare
 young ladies for the multifaceted role of women in our society.
- Coordinate, Plan, and Supervise fieldtrips 5th grade; three-day Sea camp trip to the Florida Keys (9 times!) 6th grade; four day Florida History trip to St.
- Augustine and Cumberland Island 7th and 8th grade; five day Science trip to Costa Rica Host Chinese students Students visit from the Cushman School partner school in Beijing, China and take part in our daily lessons for a period of two to three weeks.
- Committees Science Chair, Balanced Scorecard (Customer Perspective), Science Curriculum Team, STEAM Council, CLP Elementary Division.

Interests

Creative instruction style Organized and detailed Enthusiastic lecturer Multicultural background Travel experience Energetic and motivational Communicate well with students

Education

Master of Science - Earth/Space Science Ed Doctor of Philosophy Curriculum & Instruction Barry University St. Thomas University // // 2019 Earth/Space Science Ed

Clinical Educator certification Bachelor of Science Elementary Ed./ESOL/Gifted Barry University -

Already filed my MPP and 20 ESE Hours, Florida DOE # 934183, - Valid teaching certificate (Elem.Ed+ ESOL+Giffed) Exp.7/2018 // // 2003 Associate of Arts Elementary Education MDC - Support Professional Business Administration Schoevers Institute NL // // 1999 Languages

Fluent in English and Dutch; proficient in Spanish and German; rusty in French.

Skills

Art, CLP, Chinese, Conferences, Council, Dutch, Educator, Fluent in English, experiments, fashion, forms, French, German, Instructor, Instruction, LEADERSHIP, Logic, Mandarin Chinese, materials, Math, meetings, philosophy, presentations, programming, research, Robotics, Robotic, proficient in Spanish, speech, teacher, Teaching, workshops

Additional Information

 TEACHING STYLE AND TALENTS Creative instruction style Organized and detailed Enthusiastic lecturer Multicultural background Travel experience Energetic and motivational Communicate well with students